<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>About on Dartmoor Walking</title>
        <link>https://dartmoorwalking.org/tags/about/</link>
        <description>Recent content in About on Dartmoor Walking</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Simon Avery</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dartmoorwalking.org/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://dartmoorwalking.org/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://dartmoorwalking.org/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmaster, co-author: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:feedback@dartmoorwalking.com&#34; &gt;Simon Avery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-this-website&#34;&gt;About this Website
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hope is that this site will provide a clear and informative way to inspire people to enjoy Dartmoor by providing self-guided walking information and suggested routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;content&#34;&gt;Content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the photographs, routes and research for this site were taken by Keith Ryan for his &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dartmoorcam.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DartmoorCam&lt;/a&gt; website. Selected walks from there have been adapted and re-presented together with additional photos and information by myself, Simon Avery, for this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was approached in 2022 and asked if I would take over a Dartmoor website from someone who could no longer maintain it. This led to me getting in contact with Keith who, with the help of his wife, was able to transfer ownership and copyright of this and two other of his websites to me on the understanding that I would try to preserve them. &amp;ndash; Simon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keith-ryan&#34;&gt;Keith Ryan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keith was born in Cornwall and spent his working life as a Marine Biologist based at Plymouth Hoe. He loved Dartmoor and started walking it in 1969, starting his website in 2004 to document the walks with photos and informed narrative. Keith led many group walks over the moor - notably with the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dartmoortrust.org/archive&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dartmoor Trust&lt;/a&gt;, meticulously researching both geographical and human history along the way. He recorded well over 600 walks on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dartmoorcam.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dartmoorcam&lt;/a&gt;, all with many photographs, footnotes and information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keith passed away at St Luke&amp;rsquo;s Hospice in May, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simon-avery&#34;&gt;Simon Avery
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simon lives on Dartmoor and has worked on and with many people associated with it for many years. As countless others do, he loves Dartmoor, its nature and rich history. Simon worked for two years in the late 1980s as part of Dartmoor National Park Authority&amp;rsquo;s Works Department out of Station Yard, Bovey Tracey. In 2018, he also served on the Community Stakeholder&amp;rsquo;s group for the Moor than Meets the Eye project, using National Lottery money to improve Dartmoor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-website&#34;&gt;This Website
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dartmoorcam.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DartmoorCam&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful website with a huge wealth of data and Keith was rightly proud of it. Unfortunately, that size has made it somewhat difficult to navigate and use and feedback suggests it can be overwhelming. With some parts of the code dating back to 2002, it has also proved difficult to manage. The site consists of over 6,000 html files and more than 50,000 image files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hope with this site was to make some of that information more accessible and appealing to more people. By converting to a modern static site generator, it should also be easier to maintain it going forwards. It is hoped that in time, this site may grow to include other people&amp;rsquo;s favourite walks too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is not intended to replace DartmoorCam, only to share the information more widely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More walks from DartmoorCam are gradually being added to this site, and where possible, added to and extended from personal and researched knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that Keith would have approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legacy&#34;&gt;Legacy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;People give a huge amount of their time and knowledge to create websites for the benefit of other people. As custodian of Keith&amp;rsquo;s websites as well as others, I would like to make not just these websites free use, but also provide the source code to them in somewhere permanent and known so that if I am no longer able to maintain and pay for them, they will continue to exist in some form. So many useful websites have already been lost in the short time the internet has been in use, that permanent archiving is very much something I would like to provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;copyright-and-media-enquiries&#34;&gt;Copyright and Media Enquiries
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before his death, Keith transferred all Copyrights and ownership to text and images used on these Websites to Simon Avery. It is on that assertion that this website has been created from Keith&amp;rsquo;s original content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any enquiries, or requests to re-use words or images used on this or the following sites should be made to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:feedback@dartmoorwalking.com&#34; &gt;Simon Avery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ordnance Survey Maps are Crown Copyright Ordnance Survey, reproduced under Licence number 100047373&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://leafletjs.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; Copyrights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keiths-websites&#34;&gt;Keith&amp;rsquo;s websites
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As well as his website of Dartmoor walks, Keith has also written several other sites which have been preserved. Please see &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dartmoorwalking.org/links&#34; &gt;the links&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-used-in-this-site&#34;&gt;Software used in this site
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This site is made entirely from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FOSS Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux (Specifically &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;) for development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VSCode&lt;/a&gt; for page editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for static site generation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stack.jimmycai.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stack&lt;/a&gt; for the Hugo theme used, heavily modified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://utteranc.es/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Utterances&lt;/a&gt; to allow commenting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://leafletjs.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; for the Map of Walks, together with custom Perl to generate the Popups at build time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pages.cloudflare.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cloudflare Pages&lt;/a&gt; for site hosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cookies&#34;&gt;Cookies
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This website does not track your online activity or use cookies for advertising purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do not sell, trade or pass your information to others in any way. We don&amp;rsquo;t even collect it in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-cookies&#34;&gt;What are cookies?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used to make websites work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the website owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-we-use-cookies&#34;&gt;How we use cookies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use cookies to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide feedback via Utterances which, if you choose to log into Github to comment on this site, remembers who you are. Github have their own privacy policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/en-gb/web-analytics/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cloudflare Web Analytics&lt;/a&gt; runs to measure website performance. It does not track individuals and does not require opt-in to satisfy GDPR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-manage-cookies&#34;&gt;How to manage cookies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can control and/or delete cookies from your browser as you wish. Please see your browser&amp;rsquo;s documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
